This senior gentleman seems familiar.
We definitely know that
upright bearing in that scar.
It's good to see you again, Speedwagon.
I understand you're an
American oil tycoon now.
That's a bit exaggerated.
You look as young as ever straight, so.
Hard to believe we're the same age.
Hamon energy is life energy, right?
I envy you.
It has been half a century since
Jonathan Joestar made his sacrifice.
Straitzo has succeeded Master Tonpetty,
while Speedwagon has had
success building a fortune.
Together, they're headed
for Mexico to see something.
This something was discovered by a
Speedwagon-funded exploration team.
What's more is that it's a secret
known only to these select few.
I tell you, Straitzo, once you
lay eyes on this, I believe, no,
I am certain you'll feel a chill.
It's frightful enough to make even
your disciplined hair stand on end.
I find it even worse
than the terror we faced
fifty years ago when we
all battled with Dio.
I can't believe how large this space is.
And this is the reason we came here.
What?
It can't be!
A stone mask!
And there are so many of them!
It was in the fall of 1938.
I was doing my job,
just like I always did.
Eyes peeled for Mark.
You've gotta be kidding me.
You really never heard
of this fine beverage?
Oh, right.
By your accent, I'd say
you're in from England.
Tourist, huh?
No kidding.
You're gonna make the big city your home?
Well, if you want a drink, you're
gonna have to lay down some shekels.
Cash is the king around here.
The nerve of him!
You're not gonna let that
Mega steal your wallet.
Get after him!
What a patsy.
That was easy as pie.
Hey, Smokey.
Looks like I finally caught you.
Red-handed, you punk.
What are you doing on my feet, you trash?
I'm gonna make sure they
lock you up for 20 years.
Take it easy. Please, sir.
I only pinched a wallet.
I hate bottom feeders like
you preying on the public.
But see, I'm nice.
I'll do you a solid.
I'm gonna let you bring me $20 every week.
Also half of everything you glommed.
Hello?
Hey, it's the pigeon what
got his wallet lifted.
This is evidence, so
I'm gonna be keeping it.
Well now, how shall I put this?
Here is what happened.
There actually is no crime since
that wallet was a gift, Constable.
For some reason,
this six and a half foot giant of
an Englishman was covering for me.
So then, sir, would you please
return both wallet and boy?
What'd you just say?
As I said, it was a gift.
He and I are good friends.
Let him go please.
A good friend
why don't you tell
me what your good friend's name is?
Hmm what's the matter limey you want to
see what a New York pokey is like huh?
Here's a present for you.
That's
curious.
Help me understand.
Why would you do something like that?
It's just such an unsavory thing to do.
There is no reason!
I do what I like whenever
I feel like it, you fool!
But if someone wipes a book around
your face, it probably means that...
You made the wrong move, you stupid punk!
You were shot resisted arrest!
Please, try to shoot me.
But I am warning you right now.
Before you can pull the trigger,
I will have broken your finger
like a rotten matchstick.
Not from over there!
I'll blow your damn brains out!
Suddenly, his body started to
give off some sort of glow.
It was just incredible.
The soda cap blew off
and flew as fast as a
bullet straight over to
snap the cop's finger.
Oh, I gave in to my temper again.
Crap, I'm in for it.
Oh, Granny Arena's going to be furious.
She beat down two cops but
is scared of his grandma?
I'll just explain.
Granny Arena will understand
if I explain, won't she?
All right, Mr.
Pickpocket, what say we
hightail it on out of here?
He didn't know exactly how he launched
the bottle cap with such force.
He said he could always
do things like that.
Apparently,
his grandpa could do the same kind of
things, but he died at a young age.
His dad, who died in the war,
didn't have any talents like that.
His mom was gone, too.
I really owe you big time.
Everyone calls me Smokey, and I'd sure
like it if you'd tell me your name.
It's Joestar.
Joseph Joestar.
My friends call me Jojo.
What is this?
Who's that a carving of on that pillar?
That's not a carving.
He has amino acids, proteins, and cells.
And though it's faint, he
has body heat and a pulse.
We are looking at a living man!
Straightzo, understand who he
is, how long he's been there,
how he got there in the first
place, what the masks are for.
None of that matters.
We are here for one purpose only.
I brought you because
of your hormone ability,
so you can use it to utterly destroy
him while he slumbers in this stone.
And Joseph Joestar? Huh? What?
Joseph Joestar, how is he doing?
I hear he has Hamon ability
and saved your life once.
Why bring up Jojo now?
As I recall, he was but 13
years of age at the time.
Yes, quite young.
Your plane was hijacked by criminals
who wanted to hold you for ransom.
Hey, kid!
You can't stay back here, you know!
Get up front!
You're hijacking the plane and
kidnapping Speedwagon, correct?
I am only a bystander.
This is his problem.
I'm just going to read my story.
Do your business and
just leave me out of it.
Wrong answer, punk! Now move! Jojo!
Not good.
That suit was a gift from Arena.
This'll set him off for sure.
He's got no sense of self-restraint.
Control yourself, Jojo!
You fellows did know
there was the possibility
of a crash if you hijacked this plane,
did you not?
Is that Harmon? Oh, no!
What did that crazy kid do?
We're gonna crash!
Run the controls!
I can't fly, idiot!
Here, get the pilot ready,
we're going to jump!
Why can't you ever just
think things through, Jojo?
I do, in fact.
A great deal.
Mostly about how to best keep
you and Granny Iran safe.
You two are the only family that I've got.
He may have his grandfather's face,
but he's far from being a gentleman.
That was the day I discovered that
Joseph was able to use Hamon. So,
young Joseph inherited the ability to
control Hamon from his grandfather Jonathan?
Jonathan? Yes.
But why are you speaking of him now?
What the hell?
I just took the lives of all these men.
And when you lose your life, Jonathan's
grandson will know grief and anger and hate.
He will develop a
tremendous hatred for me.
No! Straitzo!
Straitzo...
Have you lost your senses? I haven't.
In fact, my thinking is extremely clear.
I chose Harmon to forge my body
into something pure and strong.
But as I trained, the aging of my
flesh became painfully clear to me.
Harmon provides only a small
advantage over ordinary people.
It cannot guard against
the process of aging.
In the battle we fought so many
years ago, I secretly admired Dio.
He was powerful.
He was beautiful.
He was immortal.
I coveted the power
granted by the Stone Mask.
I didn't care who got in the way.
You're a twisted traitor, Straitzo.
Your blood will now bring me immortality.
With you gone, the only ones to know of
the Mask will be Iran and Joseph Joestar.
And once I have disposed of them,
I shall learn more of the
mask than Dio ever could.
No, don't do it.
The knowledge you're seeking
could have terrible consequences.
Joe, Joe, breathe.
Hey, you!
Why don't you get a clue
what you're doing, dumbass?
Pull your head out of your
butt and see where you are!
Now get the hell out of my way!
Hello there! What? Didn't hear that!
I can't make it out!
Would you mind repeating all that?
I'd like to know what
it was you meant to say.
In case I have to pound you.
Jojo, what is it you're doing there?
Granny Arena I asked what
you're doing with that man?
Well, you see This man is
A taxi
This way you don't have to walk so far.
Thank you, Jojo You're
such a thoughtful boy!
Climb in, Smokey We're going for a ride.
The Joestar family Reduced to
a grandmother And her grandson.
Over time, I would hear
bits of their past.
Granny, really?
Speedwagon sent for us, and we came all the
way to New York simply because he asked.
But now we find he's not even here?
I think his behavior is quite rude.
I'm sure that the oil business
requires much of his time.
Say, Granny, I'm curious.
Was Speedwagon really
Grandpa's best friend?
Is that all it was? Come on now.
What are you implying?
Well, let's see.
He was never married, was he?
And you yourself are a widow. Well,
it leads me to wonder
if simple friendship was
the only relationship
that was going on there.
You rogue you!
Sorry! Ow!
I was wrong! Ow! Forgive me!
I know Speedwagon is loyal! Ow!
The Joestars tended to be short-lived.
Granny Arena lost her husband
in an accident at sea.
She was pregnant with a son at the time.
When he grew up, he married a girl
who would also survive the wreck.
They were JoJo's parents, later
claimed by war and disease.
Granny Arena was a gentle and giving woman,
even to punks like me, or anybody else.
Maybe it was because she
lived with loneliness.
JoJo was the same.
This time, however, his basic
kindness got him into trouble.
Thanks to me.
Hey, waiter! Waiter! Yes, sir.
Who decided that stinking animal
could be allowed in here, huh? Huh?
His smell is ruining my appetite.
That kind shouldn't be
allowed in a place like this.
I understand, sir.
But there's a policy
handed down by management.
As long as the check is paid in full,
we happily serve anyone. What was that?
You'll happily let beasts like
that do their grazing in here, huh?
Guess I'll just be on my way.
Jojo?
You heard him. Come on.
You're not going to tell
me to stop, are you? No.
People are entitled to their opinions.
But this misbegotten oaf has
given public insult to our friend.
Be mindful of the other guests
now, but teach him a lesson.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Well now, boy, looking to fight?
Let me help.
If the brass knuckles are
what you're looking for,
you are not going to find
them inside of your coat.
You might want to check your
back pocket instead. What?
No way!
Next you'll say, you bastard, how could
you have possibly known where they were?
You bastard, how could you possibly
have known where they were?
By the visible abrasions
that are on your right hand,
it's obvious that you do your
fighting using brass knuckles.
You've no wounds, so the blood
on your shirt is not from you.
Therefore, you've just come from a fight.
Since the blood is on your shirt
and not that pink horror of a coat,
it was taken off prior to the fight.
And then, after you had
completed your assault,
the knuckles came off, and that's
when you proceeded to stow them away.
in your back pocket.
For my next glimpse into the future, you
will now say, So what, you little punk?
Yeah, so what, you little punk,
and now, you're gonna get it!
I gotcha!
You like that, huh?
That'll teach you a lesson.
Sorry, you missed.
What have you been punching?
I wasn't the one you were
pummeling so happily.
Oh, my God!
I can predict and counter anything your
tiny brain is able to come up with.
Do you understand that now, you simpleton?
Please, forgive the behavior
of my underling, madam.
You're Arena Joestar, aren't you?
I've worked on a lot of
business deals with your Mr.
Speedwagon, you see.
He told me some stories about you when
him and me were in London a while back.
I'm glad to meet you.
I heard a little something
through the grapevine.
It hasn't made it into the
papers yet, but you should know.
It seems that Mr.
Speedwagon has been murdered.
Are you sure?
Rumor is the cat who did it
was some sort of Tibetan monk.
Some sort of monk?
Could it be straighter?
All they're saying is that the
bodies of Speedwagon and his
team washed up along a riverbank
somewhere down in Mexico.
It's a genuine mystery.
Nobody has any idea why they were killed,
or where the monk might
have gone to afterwards.
Actually, I think I might know.
Perhaps.
Speedwagon said something a long time ago.
It involved Dio, and the horrible
stone mask that changed him.
Jojo, that guy is a mafia man.
You can't trust what he tells you.
He's trying to pull something.
Believe whatever you want to, kid.
Hold on.
Try your breast pocket if
you're after your lighter.
Huh?
Anyway, thanks for the warning, Smokey.
But I think I believe what
this man is telling us.
These fellows are only
motivated by money. Clearly,
information like that is
valuable to his organization,
so I'm inclined to listen to him.
However...
As true as that may be,
you don't simply waltz over here and then
just blurt out awful news to Granny Iran.
Don't you see how badly upset
you've made her with this news?
You are very thoughtless!
It was 50 years ago,
and still, those events haunt us.
Don't be frightened.
I'm here, and I'll protect you.
You mustn't, Joseph.
I'm concerned for you.
I don't want you snared by
evil from a half-century ago.
I'll be fine, Granny.
If this is my fate, I accept it fully.
At the time, I didn't
understand what was going on.
But these two had an unimaginable history.
Hey, Smokey.
What's going on, Jojo?
Look at this here.
See what they're saying? What is it?
Do you think this is true?
Can girls really make them bigger?
Let's see.
Go from a double A cup to a C cup.
Right.
Just a bunch of snake oil.
Don't buy into it.
Come again?
I think $1.25 a pair is too much.
No, yes, but
I say, you look rather familiar
to me, yet somehow different?
Please tell me, have we
possibly met somewhere before?
And why isn't your breath
visible it's so cold
tonight and if my eyes
aren't deceiving me i think I
caught a glimpse of fangs
in your mouth just now
was i seeing things
don't
trifle with me i warn you
Even if it is in plain sight
on the city street Jojo
I'll take your life long before
you ever become a danger.
Or perhaps not.
I knew the man was crazy,
but not that crazy!
Right out in public? Incredible!
Where did he even get the Tommy Gun?
WHY SHOOT UP THE WHOLE CITY?!
Yes, I was awaiting you, Straitzo.
That was on behalf of Speedwagon.
But I don't think you'll
go down so easily.
Our war has begun.
I'll be the roundabout The words will make
you out and out I'll
spend the day your way
Call it morning driving through
the sun And in and out the valley
The music dance and sing They make the
children really ring I
spend the day your way
Call it morning driving through
the sun And in and out the valley
In and around the lake
Mountains come out of the
sky And they stand there
One mile over, we'll be
there And we'll see you
Ten true summers, we'll
be there Laughing with you
Twenty-four, we'll be there But
I will say I'll be there with you